(沖田)いっけねえ…｡
いよいよ 死は近い》
ｵﾚの代わりに 金魚に
ｴｻをやっといてくれないか➡
などというｾﾘﾌが それにあたる｡
死をにおわせるｾﾘﾌ
ｼﾁｭｴｰｼｮﾝを指したもので➡
《沖田:世の中には
死亡ﾌﾗｸﾞというものが存在する｡
これなどは わかりやすい例で
他のｼﾁｭｴｰｼｮﾝとしては➡
仕事帰りに 柄にもなく
ｹｰｷ屋なんぞに立ち寄り…》
《ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞのﾄｯﾋﾟﾝｸﾞしてもらうの
忘れてたなんて言いだしたら➡
ﾌﾗｸﾞが立ったあと 間もなく男は
敵組織に決死の戦いを挑み➡
命を落とし 女は泣きながら
金魚に ｴｻをやることになる｡
悪いﾔﾂが いいﾔﾂになると危ない
というものもある｡
今までの悪行を悔い改め
まっとうな道を歩みだした男｡
There are these things known
as death flags in our world.
A spoken line or situation
which foreshadows death.
(霧江)
真選組 一番隊隊長 沖田総悟｡
"Could you feed the goldfish for me?"
would apply.
父上の仇
しかと 取らせていただきました｡
Once the flag is set,
the man will soon challenge the bad
guys to a final battle and lose his life.
《誰それの恨みなのか➡
そんなことは
問いただす気にもなれない｡
The woman will feed his goldfish in tears.
それを問うには 男は➡
This example is easy to understand,
but there are other situations.
あまりにも多くの人を
傷つけてきたから｡
A bad guy who becomes a good
guy is also at high risk.
たとえ改心しようと
その罪は消えない｡
ｵﾚだけ幸せになろうなんざ
虫のいい話だったんだ｡
A man who regrets everything wrong he's done
and vows to live an honest life from now on.
男は
自嘲じみた笑顔を浮かべると➡
On his way home from work, he stops
at a cake store of all places.
静かに 地面に向かって
倒れていった｡
そして…》
"Oops, I forgot to ask them to
top it off with mayonnaise."
《男は 女の首を足でｸﾘﾝﾁし➡
女は 地面に
叩きつけられたのであった》
That's when death is really near by.
うっ… ううっ…｡
《ﾗｯｷｰなことに
男は死ななかった》
おい どうしてくれるんでい｡
Captain of the Shinsengumi First Division...
Sogo Okita.
ｹｰｷが ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬじゃねえか｡
せっかく ﾀﾊﾞｽｺ ぶち込んで
ﾊﾞｶどもに食わせようと思ったのに｡
I have avenged my father's death.
《なぜなら ｵﾚは
最初から いいﾔﾂだったからだ》
He cannot bring himself
to ask who that was...
For the man has hurt too many
people in his lifetime.
He may try to change, but those
sins will never go away.
It was selfish to seek happiness for himself.
The man had a mocking smile on his face
as he quietly toppled towards the ground.
And then...
The man locked his legs around the girl's
neck and smashed her into the ground.
As luck may have it,
the man didn't die.
Hey, how are you gonna
make up for this?
The cake's a mess now.
And I just loaded it up with tabasco
sauce for those morons to chow on.
That's because...
I was a good guy to begin with.
["Beware of Foreshadows"]
(沖田)つうことなんです｡
そのへんの非合法遊里にでも➡
There you have it.
Could you sell her off to some illegal
red light district institution?
売り飛ばしてもらえますか
この娘｡
まだｶﾞｷだが ﾏﾆｱには
高く売れますぜ｡
She's just a kid, but some
freaks pay a lot for that.
(銀時)人を
奴隷商人みたいに言うな｡
Don't make it sound like
I'm a slave trader.
あれ？ 奴隷商人じゃ
ありませんでしたっけ？
Huh? Aren't you a slave trader?
不法入国した小娘 無銭で
こき使ってるじゃないですか｡
You've got this little girl, an illegal immigrant,
working for you without pay.
(神楽)誰が奴隷ｱﾙか！
ぶち殺したろか ｸｿｶﾞｷ!!
Who are you calling a slave?!
Want me to kill you, brat?!
Don't bring trouble to me.
厄介なもん
持ち込んでくんじゃねえよ｡
こんな小娘 ﾃﾒｴらで
処理すりゃいいだろ 面倒くせぇ｡
You guys can deal with this little girl.
Such a pain...
こんなｻﾞｺに いちいち構ってたら
きりがねえや｡
There would be no end if we dealt
with every two-bit criminal around.
ｳﾁは ｵﾀｸと違って
ﾋﾏじゃねえんです｡
We're busy, unlike you people.
ただの殺人集団が 何を偉そうに｡
Pretty big-headed for a
bunch of murderers.
ﾃﾛﾘｽﾄだけじゃ飽き足らず
罪もない人間まで➡
You go off killing innocent people
along with terrorists.
No wonder you would be so busy.
斬り殺してりゃ
そりゃ ﾋﾏなんてないでしょうよ！
(新八)霧江さんって
いいましたっけ？
Kirie-san, was it?
Did your father belong to an
Anti-Foreigner Faction?
あなたの その…
亡くなったお父上って➡
攘夷浪士かなんかじゃ
ないんですか？
私が逆恨みして
こんなことをしたとでも？
Are you implying that I'm mistaken?
父は… なんの罪もない
一般市民です｡
My father was an innocent,
ordinary citizen.
この人たちは ﾃﾛから
一般市民を守るのが仕事ですよ｡
This man and his colleagues work to protect
ordinary citizens from terrorists.
そんなこと…｡
巻き込まれたんです！
They wouldn't-
He was caught up in a fight.
The Anti-Foreigner Faction and the Shinsengumi
were engaged in a chaotic brawl...
攘夷浪士と真選組
入り乱れての乱戦の中➡
父は巻き込まれ
この男に… 斬られたんです！
My father was caught in the melee
and cut down by this man.
って言ってるけど 沖田君？
知りゃしませんよ｡
So she says, Okita-kun.
I don't know anything about that.
とぼけるな!!
Don't play dumb!
Don't tell me that you've forgotten
my father, Muneharu Rokkaku!
我が父 六角宗春の名
忘れたとは言わせない！
かなわねえな｡ 斬った人間のﾂﾗ
いちいち覚えてたら➡
I can't put up with this.
If I tried to remember the face of
every person I've ever cut down,
ｵﾚは 今 ここにいやせんぜ｡
I wouldn't be here now.
そんなもん引きずってたら
こっちが斬られちまうんでね｡
If I let myself worry about that,
I'd be the one cut down.
戦場では
一瞬の迷いさえ命取りになる｡
On the battlefield, a moment's hesitation
can cost you your life.
目の前の人間を一瞬でも早く
肉塊にした者が生き残る｡
Whoever dispatches the people
before him quickest will survive.
そんな場所で紛れ込んだﾊﾟﾝﾋﾟｰと
ﾃﾛﾘｽﾄを判別するなんざ➡
It's more or less impossible
to distinguish between commoners
and terrorists on that field.
至難の技でさぁ｡
So you don't remember anything,
じゃあ 何も覚えてねえし➡
and you don't plan on denying you did it?
否定をするつもりもねえと…｡
ひとつだけ言えることは➡
All I have to say, whether or not I did it,
ｵﾚがやったにせよ
そうでないにせよ➡
んなとこで ﾓﾀｸｻやってた➡
is that it was her old man's fault for
dawdling around in that place.
鈍くせぇ ｺｲﾂの親父が
いちばん悪いってことでさぁ｡
ｷｻﾏは～!!
You son of a bitch!
Kirie-san, please calm down!
You did it!
ｷｻﾏが！
霧江さん 落ち着いて！
ｷｻﾏが 父上を殺したんだ!!
You killed my father!!
殺してやる！
絶対 絶対ｷｻﾏを殺してやる!!
I'll kill you!
I swear I'll kill you!!
惜しいね｡
A pity.
If you weren't a girl,
we'd recruit one with such spirit.
女じゃなけりゃ
ｳﾁに欲しいくらいの気骨だ｡
だが 仇討ちごっこも
ほどほどにしとくこったな｡
But no more of your revenge games.
次 ｵﾚの世界に一歩でも
足踏み入れたら➡
The next time you step into my realm,
迷わず肉塊にするぜ｡
I'll slaughter you without hesitation.
うっ!?
んじゃ 旦那 金は置いとくんで｡
Well, boss, I'll leave the money here.
あと これちょっと
潰れちゃったけど食べてくだせぇ｡
And this is a little smashed,
but you can eat it.
待て！ 許さない!!
Wait! You won't get away!
I'll never let you get away with this!
絶対 許さない!!
Kirie-san, calm down!
霧江さん 落ち着いて！
はなせ！ 殺してやる!!
Let me go!
I'll kill you!
絶対に父上の仇をとってやる!!
I swear I'll avenge my father!
霧江さん…｡
Kirie-san...
Gin-san, Kagura-chan.
銀さん 神楽ちゃん
どうしたもんでしょう これ｡
What do we do?
女だてらに仇討ちなんざ➡
A mere girl trying to avenge
her father alone...
泣かせる話ｱﾙ｡
Brings tears to my eyes...
神楽ちゃん…｡
Kagura-chan...
わかったね｡
一緒に やってやるｱﾙよ！
I understand.
I'll give you a hand.
えっ… なに？
Huh? What?
I said I'll help you kill that son of a bitch!
あの野郎を一緒に
ぶっ殺すっつってんだよ!!
ｹﾞﾎｯ！ ｹﾞﾎｯ！ あぁ…｡
There's no doubt about it!
間違いない！ 犯人はﾔﾂね！
He's the one who did it!
水！ 新八 水!!
Water!
Shinpachi! Water!
ちょっと… ちょっと神楽ちゃん!?
Wait!
I'll kill him!
Wait, Kagura-chan!
I swear I'll kill that son of a bitch!
(神楽)あの野郎 殺してやる!!
Kagura-chan!
[Kabuki Land]
The Rokkaku incident.
(桂)六角事件｡
２年前 旅籠六角屋で起こった➡
A melee between the
Anti-Foreigner Faction radicals named the Sokai Faction
過激攘夷派 創界党と
真選組による争闘事件だ｡
and the Shinsengumi which happened
at Rokkaku Inn two years ago.
同時多発的に
江戸の各地に火を放ち➡
The Sokai Factions's plan
to simultaneously set fires
中央にｽｷをつくり
将軍暗殺を企てていた創界党｡
all around Edo as a distraction for
the assassination of the Shogun.
["I have a part!"]
この計画を
実行直前に突き止めた真選組が➡
The Shinsengumi learned of
the plan at the last second
連中の潜伏していた
六角屋を急襲した｡
and assaulted Rokkaku Inn
where they were hiding.
真選組 創界党 合わせて36名もの
死者を出す大惨事となった｡
It resulted in thirty-six catastrophic deaths
between the Shinsengumi and Sokai Factions.
36名!?
Thirty-six?!
The Sokai Factions were
eradicated in this incident,
この事件で創界党の人員は全滅｡
while the Shinsengumi only
suffered three deaths.
対して真選組の死者は
たったの３名！
火急なこともあり
一番隊のうち➡
Despite the fact that they only had time to
send f-f-f-five members from the First Division.
たった５… ５名しか
出動できなかったにも関わらずだ｡
一番隊隊長 沖田総悟
六角屋の殺戮は➡
You could say that Sogo Okita,
Captain of the First Division,
carried out most of the killing at Rokkaku.
ほぼﾔﾂによって
行われたと言っていいだろう！
たった一人で 攘夷派の組織
１個潰したっていうんですか…｡
He destroyed an entire Anti-Foreigner
Faction unit by himself?
末恐ろしいｶﾞｷだね｡
Scary kid.
But even if he is the strongest
of the Shinsengumi,
だが 真選組 最強の男といえど➡
それほどの修羅場を容易に
潜り抜けられたわけではあるまい｡
he couldn't have made it through
the ordeal unscathed.
Kabuki Doggy! Kabuki Doggy!
極限の状況
極限の緊張感のなかで➡
With those extreme circumstances,
the extreme tension,
誤って六角屋の主人
宗春を斬っていたとしても➡
I wouldn't be surprised if he accidentally cut
down the owner of Rokkaku Inn, Muneharu.
なんら おかしくはない！
ｶﾌﾞｷﾜﾝｺじゃない 桂だ！
It's Katsura, not Kabuki Doggy!
ｶﾞｧｰ！
おっ？
うおっ！
なむ～｡
じゃあ 桂さんも➡
Katsura-san...
神楽ちゃんと同じく 沖田さんが
やったって言うんですか？
You agree with Kagura-chan
that Okita-san did it?
No idea.
さあな あくまで可能性を
提示したまでだ｡
I'm merely saying that it's possible.
ﾂﾞﾗ そのあと六角屋は
どうなったんだ？
Zura, what happened to the
Rokkaku Inn afterwards?
しばらくは 残った宗春の妻と娘で
切り盛りしていたらしいが➡
For a while, Muneharu's wife
and daughter kept it going,
そんな騒ぎが起こった宿を
好んで利用する者もあるまい｡
but nobody wanted to stay at
the inn after such an incident.
１年ほど前に潰れた｡
It went out of business a year ago.
His wife passed away soon after,
perhaps from the exhaustion.
心労がたたってか
妻も間もなく…｡
見てのとおりです｡
As you can see, I have nothing left.
私には もう何も残っていない｡
《父上…》
Father...
((まぎょきょろ？
Sincerity?
Yes, sincerity.
(宗春)真心だよ｡
宿屋をやる者にとって➡
The most important thing
for an innkeeper.
いちばん大切なものだ｡
お客様の身になって誠心誠意
真心を忘れずに常に接する｡
Always remember to serve customers
with a sincere heart and devotion.
でも私には
もっと大切なものがある｡
But I have something more important.
母さんと お前だよ｡
Mother and you.
ﾊﾊｯ！
お前たちのためなら 私は))
For the two of you, I would do anything...
(霧江)父上はいつも優しかった｡
Father was always so kind.
私や母上を大切にしてくれた｡
He cared deeply for Mother and me.
もう私には 父上も母上もいない｡
But Father and Mother are gone now.
帰る家もない｡ ｱｲﾂは私から
すべてを奪っていったんです｡
I have no home to return to.
He took everything from me.
なのに 何も
覚えてないなんて許せない！
And yet...!
How can he say he doesn't
remember anything?!
絶対 私 あの男を許さない！
I will never forgive that man!
銀さん ﾎﾞｸ 霧江さんが
仇討ち考えるのも➡
Gin-san, I can understand why
Kirie-san wants revenge.
わからなくもないですよ｡
でも 沖田さんを
責める気にもなれません｡
But I can't blame Okita-san either.
これは不慮の事故じゃないですか｡
That was just an unfortunate accident.
江戸を護ろうとして 起こって
しまった 不幸な事故でしょ｡
An unfortunate accident that happened
as he was trying to protect Edo.
沖田さん
覚えてないんじゃなくて➡
It's not that Okita-san
doesn't remember...
忘れたい
だけなんじゃないでしょうか？
Maybe he just wants to forget?
今さらほじくり返して
仇討ちなんてしたって➡
There's no point in digging up
the past now for revenge.
霧江さん
もっと不幸になるだけですよ｡
Kirie-san will end up suffering more.
止めないと｡
心配いらねえよ｡
We have to stop her.
You don't need to worry.
神楽がついてるだろ｡
それが心配なんでしょ！
Kagura's with her.
That's why I'm worried!
大丈夫さ ｱｲﾂはわかってるよ｡
It's fine.
The guy knows.
だてに何度も
ぶつかっちゃいねえ｡
I can tell after all our run-ins.
おかしいと思わねえか？
Don't you find it odd?
命狙ってきた相手なら➡
He's the kind of guy
who doesn't hesitate
女子供だって容赦なく
叩き斬るのが野郎だろ｡
to cut down women and children
if they're after his life.
それを殺るどころか
捕まえもせずに金まで置いて➡
Yet he didn't even try to catch her,
much less kill her,
ｵﾚたちのところに
女を預けていった｡
and left her with us
along with money.
覚えてなくなんかねえ｡
忘れたがってるわけでもねえ｡
He remembers.
He doesn't want to forget.
野郎は たぶん…｡
He probably just...
[Rokkaku Incident]
(神山)ご苦労様です 沖田隊長！
Greetings, Captain Okita!
出廻りから帰ったとみるや
資料室で勉強とは➡
Studying in the reference room
after returning from patrol.
I would expect no less from the captain!
さすがっす 隊長！
Skilled in both literary and military arts!
文武両道｡ 隊長は 侍の鏡っす！
The ideal samurai!
I will follow you forever!
自分 一生隊長について…｡
こなくていい｡
No need.
You're annoying, so make
a U-turn and leave.
うるせえから
そのままＵﾀｰﾝして帰れ｡
And you never need to come back.
一生戻って来なくていいから｡
これは 六角事件の資料ですか？
Is that the case file regarding
the Rokkaku incident?
また ずいぶんと昔の事件を｡
That was a while ago.
意外っす｡ 自分 隊長は➡
I'm surprised.
I believed the captain to be someone
who doesn't dwell on the past.
過去を振り返らない方だと
思っておりました｡
未来に進むためには ときに過去を
振り返ることも必要なんでぃ｡
Sometimes, it's necessary to look back at
the past in order to move on to the future.
Keep that in mind.
覚えとけ｡
ｲｴｯｻｰ！ ﾒﾓしときます！
Yes, sir!
I'll write it down!
If you understand, make a U-turn
and look back at the past.
わかったら そのままＵﾀｰﾝして
過去を振り返れ｡
And you never need to come
back from the past.
過去から一生
戻ってこなくていいから｡
ｲｴｯｻｰ！ ﾒﾓしときます！
ﾒﾓじゃなくて帰れって言ってんだ｡
Yes, sir!
I'll write it down!
I'm telling you to leave, not take notes.
But the Rokkaku incident
brings back memories.
しかし懐かしいですね 六角事件｡
おい 聞いてんのか？
Hey, you listening?
自分が 沖田隊長に惚れたのは
何を隠そう➡
In fact, I must admit that was
when you captured my heart.
あのときでありました！
隠してくれよ｡
Don't admit that.
頼むから 神隠しにあってくれよ｡
お願い 神様｡
Go get spirited away.
Please, God.
あれは 凶悪な攘夷浪士を
前にしたときでした｡
That was a violent bunch of
Anti-Foreigner Faction men.
次々に倒れていく仲間たち｡
One by one, our comrades
were cut down.
最後に残ったのは 隊長と自分｡
Only the captain and I were left.
互いに背中を預け 護り合い
激戦をくぐり抜けることで➡
Each watching the other's
back, guarding it.
After surviving that furious battle,
自分は 隊長を運命共同体とも
呼べるような存在と➡
I was able to recognize that my
fate was tied to the captain's!
認識するにまで至ったのです｡
お前 何もしてなかっただろ｡
You didn't do a thing.
I'd rather let a locker watch my back than you.
お前に背中預けるくらいだったら
ﾛｯｶｰに預けるわ｡
しかし なぜ今になって
六角事件などお調べに？
But why are you researching
the Rokkaku incident now?
I was stabbed by that thing.
ｿｲﾂで刺された｡
えっ？
Huh?
The daughter from Rokkaku Inn said
she was avenging her father.
親父の仇だって｡ 六角屋の娘に｡
Stabbed?!
刺された！
Are you okay?!
大丈夫なんですか？
いったいどこを！
Where were you stabbed?!
ｹﾂですか ｱﾅﾙですか ｱﾇｽですか！
The ass?!
Anal?!
The anus?!
それとも肛門ですか！
Or was it the asshole?!
Those are all the same thing.
それ全部 ｹﾂだろ｡ あのさ
いい加減にしねえと刺すよ ﾎﾝﾄ｡
Now look here.
Cut it out or I'll really stab you.
刺してください
隊長となら本望です！
Please stab me!
My dream is to die at
your hands, sir!
We told the survivors
of Rokkaku Inn
六角屋の遺族には 宗春の死は➡
that Muneharu died at the hands
of the Anti-Foreigner Faction.
攘夷浪士の凶刃によるもの と
伝えたはず！
それを 今さら なぜ？
So why now...?
It wasn't Captain Okita's fault
that Muneharu Rokkaku died!
六角宗春が死したのは
沖田隊長のせいではない！
あれは…｡
ほっとけ｡
That was...
Forget it.
ｿｲﾂは 問題じゃねえんだ｡
That isn't the problem here.
ほっとくって… まさか 隊長！
Forget it?
Don't tell me that you allowed
the girl to walk free?!
その娘 捕まえもせずに
野に放したんですか？
I'm saying that a girl or two won't
be able to give me any trouble.
あんな小娘 何人かかってこようが
問題じゃねえって言ってんだ｡
But, Captain...!
しかし 隊長！
まさか 父親を死なせたことを
気に病んで…｡
Are you upset about letting
her father die...?
それならば！
そんなんじゃねえよ｡
In that case...!
That isn't it.
ならば なぜ!?
自分 ｶﾞﾏﾝできないっす！
Then why?!
I can't bear this!
I shall prove your innocence!
沖田隊長の潔白を証明してきます｡
I'm not innocent.
潔白なんかじゃねえ｡ ｿｲﾂは
ﾃﾒｴが いちばん知ってるはずだ｡
You should be well aware of that.
You didn't do anything wrong!
隊長は
何も悪いことなんて やってない｡
I shall go tell her the truth!
全部 正直に話してきます｡
もう ｶﾞﾏﾝできません！
I can't hold it in any longer!
ほっとけって言ってんのが
聞こえねえのか？
Didn't you hear me tell you to forget it?
あの場で生き残ったのは
ｵﾚたちだけなんだ｡
We were the only survivors.
ｵﾚたちが黙ってりゃ もうこれ以上
面倒ごとは起きねえんだよ｡
If we keep quiet, there won't
be any further trouble.
But as things stand, you'll
be called a murderer...!
しかし このままでは
隊長が人殺しの汚名を…｡
人殺しにでも
なんでも なってやるよ｡
I'll become a murderer
if that's what it takes,
ﾃﾒｴが そのﾍﾞﾗﾍﾞﾗ軽い口を
閉じねえってんならな｡
if you don't stop that loose
tongue of yours.
The real question is...
問題は… そう
あの小娘が どっから➡
Yes, how did the girl find
out and come after me?
そんな話を聞いてきて
ｵﾚを狙ったかってことだ｡
あのﾔﾏを利用し 娘を焚きつけ
ｵﾚを殺ろうとしたﾔﾂがいる｡
Someone is trying to kill me through
that girl by using that incident.
That's why you're reading the case file?
それで 資料を…｡
(沖田)その脇差し 見てみろ｡
Look at that short sword.
使い古された いい刀だ｡
A good blade that's been well-used.
だが 一介の町人の娘が
廃刀令のご時世に➡
But why would the daughter
of an ordinary citizen
be carrying such a thing when
swords have been banned.
なぜ そんなもん
持ってやがるんでぃ？
黙らせなきゃならねえ連中が
まだ いる｡
There are still people who
need to be silenced.
あのとき
六角屋で生き残ったのは➡
We might not have been the
only survivors at Rokkaku.
ｵﾚたち 真選組だけじゃ
ないのかもしれねえ｡
神山 もう一度
このﾔﾏ 洗ってこい｡
Kamiyama, go see what
you can sniff out.
And wipe that bloody ass, too.
ついでに
その血だるまの きたねぇｹﾂもな｡
Y-Yes, sir!
ｲ… ｲｴｽ ｻｰ！
(土方)総悟が 陰でｺｿｺｿやってる？
Sogo is sneaking around?
Yes, he's behaving suspiciously.
(山崎)えぇ どうにも
怪しい動きをしてまして｡
誰かだか刺されただぁ
ｵﾚを刺してくれだぁ➡
Talking about being stabbed
by someone.
"Stab me."
ｹﾂ 洗ってこいだぁ 神山と２人で
なにやら ｺｿｺｿ 話してるんです｡
"Go wipe your ass."
He was whispering about something
with Kamiyama.
Yamazaki...
山崎…
いくら 監察といってもな➡
Even if you're keeping an eye on him,
そういう…
ﾌﾟﾗｲﾍﾞｰﾄな？ 性的な嗜好？
private information like, uh,
sexual preferences...
そういうところまで 探りを入れて
介入するというのは➡
should stay off-limits, I would say.
いかがなものだろう？
副長？
Vice-chief?
I'll pretend I didn't hear anything.
今回のことは
聞かなかったことにしよう｡
ｵﾚとお前の胸の内に
しまっておこう｡
This information doesn't leave the room.
副長…
何 勘違いしてるんですか？
Vice-chief, you're mistaken.
どうやら 沖田隊長
命 狙われてるようなんです｡
It seems that someone's
after Captain Okita's life.
六角事件を覚えていますか？
Do you remember the Rokkaku incident?
あのﾔﾏはとっくに解決しただろう｡
Wasn't that business
dealt with long ago?
Yes...
えぇ しかし 沖田隊長が
この資料を調べていました｡
But, Captain Okita was
reading this case file.
何か つながりがあるようで｡
I believe there's a connection.
もともと あの事件
生存者は あの２人だけ｡
Those two were the only survivors
from the incident.
報告にも
不審な点が多かったんです｡
And there were oddities in the report.
あの２人 なにか
隠しているのかもしれません｡
The two of them might
be hiding something.
[Rokkaku Incident]
六角事件か…｡
The Rokkaku incident, huh?
あの娘… じゃねえな｡
ﾃﾒｴか？ あのｶﾞｷ けしかけたのは｡
You're not that girl, are you?
So you were the one
who set her after me.
ったく… どいつも ｺｲﾂも
そんなに ｵﾚが憎いかね｡
Man, do you all hate me so much?
Yeah, I hate you!
あぁ 憎いね！ よくも ﾀﾊﾞｽｺなんて
仕込みやがったな ｸｿｶﾞｷゃ!!
How dare you mix in Tabasco
sauce, damn brat?!
ｵﾒｴかよ!!
何をしてんだ!? ﾃﾒｴは！
It's you?!
What are you doing?
万事屋は儲からないから
廃業して 殺し屋に転向したｱﾙ｡
Doing odd jobs doesn't make any money,
so I quit and became a hitman.
Raise your hands.
手 上げろ｡ おかしなﾏﾈしたら
ﾄﾞﾀﾏ ぶち抜くど！
Any funny moves and I'll
pop you in the kisser.
You're the one who's funny in the head.
おかしいのは ｵﾒｴだろ｡
自分のﾄﾞﾀﾏ ぶち抜けよ｡
Pop yourself in the kisser.
You might become able
to think straight, then.
少しは ましな思考が
できるようになるぜ｡
生意気な口
きいてんじゃねえぞ ｺﾗ！
Don't give me lip, damn it.
Show some respect.
敬語でしゃべれ｡
状況 わかってんのか？ うん？
Do you understand the situation
you're in, huh?
Want me to spell it out for you?
ひらがなっぽく
しゃべってやろうか？
All nice and slow so an idiot
like you can understand?
お前みたいなﾊﾞｶでも
わかりやすいように➡
全部 ひらがなっぽく
しゃべってやろうか？
Could you please leave?
頼むから 帰ってくれませんか｡
あなたみたいなのに➡
I don't have time to deal
with someone like you.
構ってるﾋﾏはないんです ﾎﾞｸは｡
やればできるじゃないか｡
So you do have manners.
よし ご褒美に ﾊｯﾋﾟｰﾀｰﾑをやろう｡
All right, I'll reward you with a Happy Term.
[Note: From "Happy Turn", a Japanese rice cracker.]
塩を全部 舐めきった ふやけて
もう ﾊｯﾋﾟｰでもなんでもない➡
A Happy Term that's all swollen
after the salt was licked off
and became an Unhappy Term.
ｱﾝﾊｯﾋﾟｰﾀｰﾑをくれてやろう｡
ぶち殺してぇ｡
神様 ﾎﾞｸは死んでもかまいません｡
I want to kill you.
God, I don't care if I die.
かわりに このｸｿｱﾏも
ぶち殺してください｡
ﾌﾝ！
So please kill this damn bitch in return.
で あのｶﾞｷは？ どうせ 一緒に
ｵﾚを殺りにきたんだろう？
So? Where's the kid?
You probably came to kill me together.
お前なんか殺したって
霧江の手が汚れるだけｱﾙ｡
Killing you will only make
Kirie's hands dirty.
じゃ 何しに来た？
Then why are you here?
Are you going to be my bodyguard?
ｵﾚのﾎﾞﾃﾞｨｶﾞｰﾄﾞでも
してくれるってのかい？
ﾎﾝﾄのこと 話すｱﾙ｡ お前が
何か隠しているのは お見通しね｡
Tell me the truth.
It's obvious that you're hiding something.
お前が 敵味方間違って
斬りかかるほど➡
I know that you're too skilled to
mistake an ally for an enemy.
しょっぱい使い手じゃ
ないことくらい お見通しｱﾙ｡
What are you trying to hide by
pretending to be a murderer?
人殺しの罪までかぶって
いったい 何を隠そうとしてるね｡
霧江の前で
きっちり しゃべるｱﾙ｡
Tell Kirie to her face.
しゃべらないってんなら➡
If you refuse, I'll punch a hole
in your face for Kirie.
霧江の代わりに
私が お前のﾄﾞﾀﾏ ぶち抜くね｡
敵味方間違って
斬りかかるほど ﾔﾜじゃねぇ…｡
I am too good to mistake
an ally for an enemy...
たしかに｡
That's true.
だが…
もし その味方と思ってたﾔﾂが➡
But...
What if someone you thought
to be an ally was an enemy?
敵だったとしたら どうする？
Some things in this world aren't
meant to be known, little girl.
(沖田)世の中にはなぁ➡
知らねぇほうがいいことも
あるのさ お嬢さん｡
それにな… ｶﾞﾗでもねぇこと➡
Besides, you shouldn't go off talking
out of character like that.
そう ﾍﾟﾗﾍﾟﾗ
しゃべるもんじゃねぇぜ｡
See? You've triggered my death flag.
見ろ｡ ﾃﾒｴのせいで
死亡ﾌﾗｸﾞが立っちまった｡
(神楽)霧江!?
Kirie?!
♪♪～
誰っすか？
大声あげんなよ｡
Who is it?
Don't raise your voice,
or the secret investigation you're hiding
from your comrades will be for nothing.
せっかく 仲間にも内密で
極秘捜査してたのが➡
ﾊﾟｰになっちまうぜ｡
Rokkaku survivor, Kamiyama-san.
六角事件の生き残りの神山さんよ｡
Wh-Who are you?
お… お前は！
ちょっと 話 聞かせてくれるか？
Could you answer a few
questions for me?
野郎が 何を隠してんのか｡
What's that bastard hiding?
お前らが 六角事件とやらで➡
What did you do during
the Rokkaku incident?
いったい… 何やらかしたのか｡
(沖田)こんな いい天気の日に
揃って仲よく 仇討ちですか｡
All these people gathered on
such a nice day for revenge?
精が出るねぇ｡
You've got spirit.
Like you're ready to raid Kira's mansion.
[Note: A reference to the Japanese fiction tale "Chusingura".]
吉良邸にでも討ち入りに
行きそうな勢いじゃねぇか｡
ｵﾒｴの親父さん
よっぽど 人に好かれてたのか…｡
They must have loved your old man.
Or they must really hate me.
それとも ｵﾚが
よっぽど 嫌われてんのか…｡
霧江！
Kirie!
Don't move.
(天堂)動くんじゃないわよ｡
父親に続いて 娘の命まで
奪いたくないのなら｡
If you don't want to take the daughter's
life after taking the father's.
ねぇ… 人殺しの沖田総悟さん｡
Right, Mr. Sogo Okita the murderer?
♪♪～
((神山 いいか…｡
Kamiyama, listen to me.
今 見たことは
すべて… 忘れるんだ｡
Forget everything you just saw.
六角屋は
ｵﾚたちが気づいたときには➡
Rokkaku was already dead
when we found him here.
ここで すでに死んでいたんだ｡
乱戦に巻き込まれ
浪士どもの凶刃にかかってな))
He was caught up in the battle and
killed by the Anti-Foreigner Faction.
♪♪～
(天堂)証拠隠滅 事後処理に追われ
生き残りを捕り逃がすなんて➡
After concealing evidence
and changing the facts,
it was foolish of you to allow
a survivor to escape.
ﾎﾝﾄに ﾏﾇｹな坊やだこと｡
The Sokai Factions weren't wiped out.
創界党は滅んじゃいない｡
It was revived to get revenge...
あなたに復讐するため… いや➡
No, to crush you all.
あなたたちを潰すために
こうして よみがえったのよ｡
I've gotten caught up in your trouble.
完全に巻き込まれたｱﾙ｡
どうしてくれるね おい！
How you gonna make up for this?
ざまぁみろ｡ いい気味だ ｸｿ女｡
Serves you right.
That's what you get, damn girl.
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
C-Captain!
I won't be able to bear
watching you tied up,
abused, stabbed, and
suffering next week!
I can't sit idly by anymore!
Please shut up.
Yes, sir!
The next episode...
"It's Goodbye Once a Flag is Set."
[Kagura and Okita are caught in a trap laid
by the Sokai Factions survivor, Sotatsu.]
[The death flags keep coming.
What really happened at the Rokkaku Inn?]
[See you next time.]